Today, I sat down with Felipe and Noah of Thea Capital.
Thea is a crypto investment fund focused on investing in liquid tokens over long time horizons.
I've had the pleasure of knowing the Thea team since they got started in early 2022,
and I think of them as without a doubt some of the best in the business.
Our discussion touches on identifying opportunities among a wide frontier,
crypto's institutional capital base and the extent of venture activity over hedge funds,
finding the best founders, and exciting themes going forward.
I hope you enjoy our conversation.
The federal government loans American international group AIG $85 billion.
This is a different kind of market and the Fed is asleep.
The federal government is stepping it to stabilize Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac,
the two mortgage giants that have been threatened by the housing crisis.
The bank of England has pumped 75 billion pounds more to Britain's ailing economy
with a new round of quantitative easing.
You print a couple trillion dollars and all of a sudden people start to worry.
So out of this worry, we have something called the Bitcoin. Bitcoin.
Felipe and Noah from Thea Capital.
Thanks for coming on the podcast today.
I'll start off by saying I have an immense respect for you guys and what you built.
I'm looking forward to having this conversation.
I think you guys have built an exceptional reputation, the crypto ecosystem,
and excited to hear your latest insights with that in mind.
I'll start off with, I think there's a lot of noise in the crypto and crypto asset space right now.
Digital asset treasuries, people talking a lot about that.
I think people are trying to assess what has value in the frontier of tokens,
especially when we're going to see more on-chain assets in the near future.
So I wanted to know, what do you make of that current landscape?
And in that wide range, how do you guys find qualified opportunities
and what makes it a qualified opportunity for you?
Why? Thanks for having us on.
Again, we echo the sentiment.
We have immense respect for you and the Castle Island team.
So thank you very much.
Yeah, on that question, I'll take a cut.
I know Noah has a lot of thoughts on this,
but we've been investing in the market for about four years now.
And one of the nice things about the crypto market
is you get to really speed run a career in investing in terms of your emotional control
and ability to interact with volatile markets.
So when I was doing private equity investing,
I would read all of these bubble letters where he talked about the one or two years
where prices were above his, really far above his estimates,
what that did to him emotionally.
And I'd read that from other investors too.
But it's never really happened in my time in the industry.
Things are more or less the same year and year out.
In crypto, you have massive volatility.
So you get to experience the full range of deep fear
when moon is collapsing and GBTC is trading 30% under
and also see people talking about AI agents
and like wonder to yourself,
is this a big thing that I'm missing?
And you get to do that multiple times in a year.
I think right now we're in a profitier period.
That seems to be the case across all financial markets.
It didn't start with us,
which is a little different from the other ones,
or more of an offshoot of what's happening
in broader financial markets and equities, gold.
Today, the Fed might be lowering rates into an all-time high market.
We all know the backdrop.
But it does seem like most tokens we look at today are overvalued
based on our estimate of going forward from the mentals and growth.
And that's not the majority.
That's just most things that we're looking at our pasts today.
We don't take a view on markets.
We don't time markets.
We don't try to predict where they'll go.
But we do try to keep our underwriting box constant over time.
So we just naturally find ourselves buying a lot more
when markets are going down or depressed,
because a lot more things just fall into our box of good value.
And we find ourselves passing a lot more in times like this
when there's fewer tokens that fit into our box.
Noah, I want to hear your view as well.
But Felipe, just on that, I wanted to say quickly,
I completely agree that you see more of these,
what I'd call market regimes in crypto.
But I'd also even just say in this period,
called the last five or six years with the crypto markets actually been mature,
it's been a tumultuous market even from a traditional landscape.
You're a bit older than I am,
but I started falling markets closely in probably the late 2010s.
And you look at like 2016, 17, 18, 19 is a lot of the same.
But then you look at like 2021, 22, 24,
you've seen four or five different markets in a period of as many years,
which is very abnormal in traditional markets.
But Noah, please, I want to hear your views as well.
I agree with Felipe's sentiment on the market
and that it's generally the opportunities are aggressively priced.
And I think part of that, if I were to steelman,
why the market has coalesced on this aside from broader financial market dynamics,
is that KPIs on chain have generally inflected quite positively.
And also there is a regulatory tailwind for our market.
So for example, Athena USDE outstanding is grown from
maybe 5 billion to 13 billion over the past three to six months.
And Abe has all time high bra activity.
And so you see KPIs moving upwards, but simultaneously,
I think that given that the base asset prices in our markets
play such a large role in the on chain metrics for financial applications,
you have to attempt to have an opinion on what's driving those prices.
And as you alluded to earlier,
I think that the digital asset treasuries are quite material
as to how markets are moving.
So for most of 2024 and the start of 2025,
micro strategy was dominant digital asset treasury strategy,
perhaps not fully correlated, but Bitcoin outperformed
eth and soul and a lot of the flows into Bitcoin were coming from micro strategy.
And then when micro strategy started issuing many different instruments
and its premium to nav started to compress,
we saw weakness in BTC and simultaneously we saw deaths emerge for eth and
soul. And so there were net positive flows coming from deaths into eth and soul
and perhaps a bit of a headwind in the short term to BTC.
So I think that probably is a large driver why eth and soul have outperformed in the short term.
And given that eth and soul are the largest collateral assets in lending markets
and the basis rate, for example, plays a large component and yields on chain,
there are these reflexive dynamics.
I think what I'm personally wary of is that while it's hard to properly
scribe fair value to eth and soul, given that they're not necessarily cash flow oriented
assets, it's hard to model out, you have to wonder whether the current prices are sustainable
if the debt buying pressure subsides in the short term.
So I think that's the other dynamic play as far as you have the KPIs inflecting upwards.
Part of it is tailwinds in our industry, part of it is flows into the base assets.
And those drivers of flows probably are in the midterm unsustainable.
So I think there's some risk on eth and soul prices.
And as a byproduct, a lot of the DeFi projects that use these assets,
is there primary generators of revenue?
Why, if you don't mind, we'll click on this question a little more.
There's a lot here.
I think that the other component that makes this a tough question right now,
and since the election is, I think our thesis that day is that we are in the early stages of
escrow adoption for the broader technology, the internet finance technology.
So I think in our view, in 15 years, a lot of the world will run on chain,
whether it's in lending markets, trading, remittances, stable coins, what you will.
And that's obviously, those are really, really big numbers.
So when you're in an early part of an escrow, you shouldn't be too split about something double
and tripling.
It can actually grow 100x from the base.
That is the case, again, for some of these base markets like stable coins,
real world assets, lending on chain.
And we now have the green light from the regulatory regime in the United States to embark on that.
It is kind of a clean cut with the situation a year ago,
where you just weren't allowed to build these products.
The tricky part is that there has been a lot of money lost in liquid markets,
trying to get the beginning of an escrow that wasn't there.
I think we've all seen this, narratives where the world is going to change.
I mentioned the AI agents as an example.
Honestly, DeFi in 2022 was that supercycle escrow that didn't pan out.
Every new L1 is the beginning of a new escrow of adoption.
People have really lost a lot of money in liquid markets,
trying to play that game.
But again, you need to be right about it,
because you lose a lot of money if you're wrong.
Things re-rate fast, and the liquidity is gone on the way down.
And you can make a lot of money if you're right.
So I think we try to really balance out the two forces of understanding,
look, there is this regulatory barrier that's been lifted,
and we have this huge opportunity ahead of us.
And there are some big winners that can take advantage of that.
I will discuss some of that in this podcast.
I mean, the names that you might, we've discussed in the past,
like Maple, Euler, Morpho, Camino.
These can be big winners over time,
but you don't want to get it wrong.
You don't want to mistake reflexive activity,
token going up, incentive rewards, driving KPIs for real growth.
Because again, that can go away in an instant,
and liquidity is gone when the paradigm shifts.
I think that's a great point.
Things move fast in this industry naturally,
and it can go very well, and it can go very poorly.
Felipe, to your point, I completely agree with the perspective
that something like a 2-3x outcome can happen quickly.
And that's not even a sign of irrationality necessarily.
It's just that we're inflecting quickly.
And also because of the early liquidity
behind a lot of these assets, you have market discovery faster.
And that's no different than the sorts of valuation step-ups
you saw in early software or you saw on early internet.
So I think that makes a lot of sense.
I wanted to pull on a few different threads
that you guys threw out already,
because I think there were several points worth double clicking on.
One, as we're talking about the way that this market behaves
and token values widely, and Noah, you touched on this,
so maybe I'll ask you to circle back.
My viewpoint, you can look at equity markets,
you can also look at token markets,
is that there are two very broad ways to view
what these things should collectively be valued.
One is a little bit more bottom-up
where you're assessing what a business should be worth,
you're potentially applying a multiple.
Whether that's value or growth,
you're trying to determine its own value or relative value.
And the other philosophy is a bit more the top-down like market liquidity,
which is how much capital is flowing into this market.
Stan Druckenmiller takes a bit of this kind of approach.
And relatedly, you'll have these massive asset managers.
Crypto has their own, they're just smaller scale,
that are assessing whether they want to be in government debt
or whether they want to be in equities
or whether they want to be in other sorts of loan financing.
And I'd say this market-wide liquidity analysis is more of that ilk.
It's looking at where is that capital going to gravitate
and how will that impact the valuations of companies today.
So, how do you guys weigh these two philosophies
of saying whether crypto protocols should be valued according to
their own fundamentals versus as something of a product
of the amount of liquidity or capital in the crypto market?
I think that the two ways that you're framing things
are correlated in that I think that liquidity in an asset class
is partially a function of the attractiveness of the opportunity.
And that is based on bottom is up analysis.
So, if a market has a lot of growth prospects
and trades relatively cheaply,
I'd imagine that more capital will flow into allocators hands
and flow into these assets.
I think that as far as framing of pure valuation,
personally I ascribe to the view that the only way to value an asset
is based on future cash flows discounted to the present.
I think there are ways to assess what an asset can trade at any given moment.
To your point, I think liquidity plays a large role in how assets trade.
And I think that there's a fair amount of alpha
in having a general view on where flows are going to move.
But that's generally a game that we have chosen
not to focus too much of our time on.
You had to pick, I think you had to pick one if you're building a firm.
Are you trading flows or are you buying a whole firm looking for fundamentals?
And we're firmly in the latter camp.
We're always underwriting three-year models.
We hope that we can hold companies for much longer than three years
to continue to execute.
I think whenever we get into a new investment,
our hope is that we're looking at something that can,
we can grow for 10 years with the management team
as they take on a really big market.
And that's been the way that a lot of funds have made great returns over time.
I would argue that the base rate of doing well as a fund is much higher
if you're doing long-term fundamentals investing
than if you're doing flows.
It's very easy to blow up trading flows.
People have done it well.
Drag them there to your point.
It's a small minority of super juices that have done that well.
Whereas the reality is if you go to any good market P firm,
any decent PC firm, you see a lot of people who have done well
playing the game that we're playing,
which is picking good companies, good management teams,
good markets, holding for the duration of the growth period.
And you guys, founders will speak very highly of you for this, rightfully.
So you're very involved typically with companies and management.
I don't know if I want to say management companies,
management of protocols or of projects.
Why have you taken that approach besides it being
a creative to the investments that you guys make?
And do you see others in the market doing that?
Did you see a gap in doing so?
Or how do you look at that sort of investor behavior
a little bit akin to some of those strategies you mentioned,
Felipe, of being middle market
or working with folks in a traditional finance sense?
Yeah, I think one, that was both of our backgrounds.
So by background with mid-market private equity,
you work very closely with companies.
In that case, you'd own 100% of the company.
So basically you're getting every dollar of accretion.
So it's a strong incentive for the sponsor
to work with the portfolio company.
Noah worked in venture capital.
I'll let him expand on it, but also work closely with companies.
But we also just really saw a big gap.
We're a liquid fund.
Usually we're buying tokens where unlocks have starter or well underway.
It's not a hard rule, but that just tends to be where we play.
And what we noticed is that the VC ecosystem was very well-served.
When your private's still yet to launch a token,
there are a lot of people in crypto who are willing to talk to you
and give you advice and a lot of very high quality VC funds.
Once the token launches, we've noticed that most of those VC funds
move on to the next batch of companies.
And these management teams that are now quite experienced
in other markets well don't have anyone to really speak to.
Or maybe they'll have one or two people to speak to on a routine basis.
And just kind of showing up as they are and saying,
we're happy to just be helpful.
Help with blocking, tapping on, recruiting, structuring,
thinking through market dynamics, sharing analysis,
and exchange.
Let us help you think through strategy questions.
Was an appealing value proposition for a lot of these liquidity founders
who just didn't have them to go to speak to anymore.
And for us, it's really valuable for two reasons.
One is we run a pretty concentrated portfolio.
So any one time there are, try to run between 10 and 15 companies.
But at any one time, there are like seven to 10 companies
that are really going to drive our return for the next 12 months
just because of the way sizey shapes up or growths for dentaries shape up.
So helping those companies at all really makes a material impact
in our portfolio if we can be helpful.
And the second is just we get really valuable market color
from these relationships.
Because usually where we're playing the 100 to billion dollar token range,
like the market leader in a segment,
you're talking to the best founder in that segment usually,
or a top three founder in that segment.
And if you speak to them week after week,
see what they're concerned about, see what they're thinking about,
you really get a lot of valuable context
that you just can't get any other way.
So I think for us, I'm very happy that our portfolio companies
are happy that we're involved,
but we're really getting a ton of value from it.
It's something that they're giving us more than we're giving them.
So I appreciate them taking a time with us really.
Yeah, I guess I'll add a bit.
I think that there's a lot of typically based point brand
and network value that come from being supportive
to portfolio companies and that I think that
although we play in liquid markets,
a lot of the time we need the opt-in of management teams
to want our support and be willing to hear our feedback.
And additionally, a lot of this industry is network driven.
There's very few major players in the space
having relationships with these players and them feeling confident
that when you make a recommendation to work with a specific service writer
to take that introduction, I think it's quite helpful.
And additionally, when we're trying to source potential investments,
having founders want to speak with us and be on their cap table
is something that's accretive to the fund generally speaking.
I agree with a lot of what you guys have said, frankly.
One point I wanted to come back to was,
I agree, Felipe, with your characterization,
I'd almost call it the over-venturization of crypto.
Everything's a venture fund.
And I think this stems, frankly,
to the appetite of capital from the outside looking in
where allocators are comfortable with the venture structure
because you're shielded from the direct volatility a little bit.
You only have to believe that crypto will be sizable in the future versus now.
But I'm curious, my point there would be,
from your guys' view, I agree that valuations
are still pretty expensive across crypto liquid markets.
You can only infer what that means for the private markets
when we're overvalued in the liquid markets
and we have a disproportionate venture participation.
That means we have to be massively overvalued
in some forms on the venture side.
And with that in mind, most of the capital being on the venture side,
who do you guys look at as the downstream investors of what you're doing?
Especially when we have this very disproportionate capital stack
where most of the money is in venture?
Important question.
And I think that's some level that's the heart of the fundamental strategy.
We consider ourselves to be the holder of these companies
and our exit liquidity, so to speak.
These happy customers paying for a service,
providing revenue to the business.
And that model is not innovative, it works well.
Look at any company on the Berkshire balance sheet.
Buffett is not selling to an exit liquidity larger investor.
When you buy Coca-Cola, you are getting your exit liquidity from the customers
who pay Coca-Cola and you get that money back as dividends.
Same goes to the Apple, same goes with any major company
that's become too large to have your buyer on the back end.
And that's why we're so focused on revenue, cost structure, cash flows.
Because there is no, right now, there is no downstream investor
to buy our tokens on a story.
We need the customers to buy the products of our companies
to give us cash, to give us cash flows,
to support evaluations, to give us an exit.
So that's really the heart of it.
I think this idea of exit liquidity has been a huge problem for the industry, in my view.
It's created this haze of just greater fool theory everywhere.
How can I split up a narrative to sell this to some outside investor?
When is retail coming?
You hear that all the time.
When is retail here?
When is retail coming?
That's basically asking when will greater fools come
and buy my tokens that have no value for me?
And we just refuse to play that game.
We know that they're not.
We know at our size, at our size, and where we play in the timeline.
It's not going to happen for us.
So we just really need to think through the fundamental question on these businesses.
One really interesting point is why is there so much venture in crypto versus liquid?
And there's been a lot of debate about this.
There's one prevailing view that there should be a lot more liquid.
That's a fair view.
But I think that there's structural reasoning that's very easy to blow up as a liquid fund.
Internally, we call this day as patience theorem, which basically,
if you don't blow up and you just keep building your skill set, at some point,
you will be the guaranteed top-dead sell player in the liquid space.
And I think that's true.
And basically, since we started, there's been a 30% attrition rate in liquid funds per year.
That's an insane number compared to any other kind of asset class.
And the reason why is the markets are so volatile.
It's so easy to re-position around.
You can blow up by taking leverage.
Of course, you know that.
I think in liquid token markets, taking leverage is basically suicide.
I don't know how to go do that.
You can blow up by going short.
Look, it's very appealing to go short.
Sometimes you see something that's vaporware valued at $5 billion.
But then you get a ripple outcome.
Your fund is over.
You can blow up through high watermark.
I don't know.
That's an interesting one people don't think about.
But if you have a team and you have a 10x year on some very speculative trade and it's down,
this literally happened with Virtuous, by the way.
It peaked on December 31st.
It peaked at Kerry Cut-Off.
And then it went down 80% after that.
And look, if that was a big part of your fund and you have a team of 10,
people are now looking at your fund saying, hey, you're not going to clip Kerry for five years.
So it's a hard position to be in as a fund.
And then people also just temperamentally, people who invest and run liquid funds often,
smaller ones.
Many people don't want to retire.
Honestly, we don't want to retire.
We want to work till we die.
Or this I do.
I know I just too, but I want to speak for him.
But some people just, you have a good year.
You make $5 million, $10 million, and you retire.
And then you're out too.
So there's not a lot of liquid funds at track of goods to go raise that capital.
And I do think a lot of it is preference for VC, the VC valuation policy.
I don't even think it's for VC.
I think it's for the valuation policy of getting to the side with companies worth
of a quarter and suppressing it all that way.
But I do think a lot of it is just there's not a lot of liquid funds that are around.
And a lot of people have come into the liquid fund industry,
but it's just the failure rate is so high.
It completely makes sense.
And I'm aligned.
I wanted to touch on your point about on-chain adoption,
Felipe had mentioned this, and internet financial systems.
The main question I have there is, I think we see a lot of companies,
existing companies, traditional companies at scale,
that are discussing putting assets on chain.
And this has been talked about for a while,
but in the wake of recent regulation, genius, and hopefully clarity coming up,
I think it's much more reality.
Do you have strong conviction that Web 3, I hate the term Web 3,
crypto-native protocols and companies will be the beneficiaries?
Of this, or do you have any concern that the next wave of on-chain finance might not benefit
proportionately these companies and protocols that we're so familiar with?
I personally lean towards latter for 90% plus of companies,
but I also think that this is a power law driven market.
So, I imagine the 10% of companies that can cross the chasm to offer products to a broader
audience will be worth a considerable amount more than where they trade today.
But I think that a lot of the way that crypto-nativism has played out has been very insular.
So, a lot of the products that have been built for crypto-natives
don't necessarily resonate with the broader market.
I also think that's okay.
I think that if you look at hyperliquid, for example,
the top 2000 traders account for a very large amount of revenue.
So, I think that when you look at a trading platform, it tends to be power law driven as well,
where the most active traders are driving most of the activity.
So, I don't necessarily think that for some of these projects you need a substantial increase
in the amount of users, just because I think that the users that can use these products
and generate a lot of revenue are already using them.
I think that depending on which market segments we're looking at within on-chain finance,
some will work as back-end technologies for existing fintechs that perhaps have built-in
compliance and regulatory features, have consumer applications that users already have a defined
behavior with.
So, I think that's one way across the chasm.
But in general, I think that companies in the crypto space today are going to need to find
ways to have their products more easily resonate with the broader audience in a way that I don't
think they currently do.
And if I added one thing to that, I would say is crypto teams need to understand that the
amount of the work ethic and level of seriousness required to cross into fintech is just substantially
higher than what they have been used to over the past five years.
This kind of remote first, work a few hours, live in Bali culture that crypto has been in
is purely a product of regulatory hurdles keeping fintech away from our markets.
And now that those hurdles are gone and these thousand person work 12 hours a day teams in
San Francisco and New York are coming into the industry, you'll have to match that to compete.
And there are a lot of founders who do match that and they work hard and they're thoughtful and
they don't try to coast off being Ethereum OG or Twitter account.
I think they'll do well because they have a head start.
But people who think they can sustain their prior lifestyles and compete with Vlad from
Robinhood are going to be sadly mistaken.
Yeah, there's no free lunch.
No.
How do you go about identifying these sorts of people, the sorts of people that you guys
want to work with and the leaders that you want to work with?
I'd say it's not that hard to know who matches the criteria.
The Green Oaks founder had a nice line in a, in that's like the best podcast.
Yeah.
He said every bad founder is different, but all good founders look the same.
And I think that's approximately true.
Like people who are hardworking, present well, obviously are doing what they love and building
in a market that they want to build in for decades.
And all they think about is their business and their competitors.
When you see them, you know who they are, right?
This is Marius.
This is Marius Rucomino.
This is Sid from Maple.
This is Paul Pomarfo and those teams, Michael from Oiler.
Like there are people who are born to build these businesses and I would take them over
anybody on the C-suite at Robinhood any day and a one-on-one matchup.
And you know who they're not.
People who are trying to retire or chasing narratives.
People who are angel investing, spending half the time angel investing,
while being the founder of a pre-revenue startup.
People who are just kind of throwing a jargon and hoping something sticks
without having a real view on the market.
I think I'd say this is one of the easier things to separate down our middle and say,
these are the founders that can really build a big business.
And you have founders that just are trying to maybe extract, maybe sell a dream and get out,
or maybe they're honest builders, but they just don't have the work ethic and the commitment
that it takes.
I agree with everything Felipe said.
The only thing that I'll add is that given the stage of companies that we're typically looking at,
I think it's a bit easier for us to identify founder quality relative to a pre-seed or seed in
that we also have a track record for how the founder has reacted to a lot of different events
within their business.
So one example that I think has been a pretty good pattern matching exercise has been founders
that have survived a bear market in crypto and are continuing to work and have not made any
unethical decisions or short-term decisions while being put in a top position.
In general, that has been indicative of the ethics, drive and founder and et cetera.
I think that's the other angle here in that we have the market do a fair amount of screening for
us before we tend to see opportunities just given that we're investing in projects that are,
I would say, around the club and to like a series A in the venture space.
I agree, Noah, and I think you guys probably look at these opportunities as much as anyone
else in the market, but I think there's an underappreciation of people.
And Michael and Sid, who you mentioned, I think are the perfect examples of this,
but have a lot of stick-to-itiveness and now market reps and a proven track record.
I'm curious for your guys' view.
I unfortunately think we're at a bit of a lull in this regard, but I think we'll come back
in the number of those people that we have in the industry and that we're attracting.
I think there are a couple reasons for that.
I think the meme coin mania had an adverse impact on the talent and profiles of people that we've
drawn into our industry, which I think is temporary, but I do think it was a headwind.
And I think that there are a lot of really interesting things happening outside of the
crypto industry. When you think about AI, when you think about robotics, that also draw talent
relative to maybe what you would have seen three, four years ago.
So I'm curious for your guys' view on how many people are you seeing like that?
Are you meeting where you feel excited to potentially work with them?
And how is that a headwind, a tailwind in your investment approach and strategy?
We are not seeing enough of those people. I know you're not seeing enough of those people
either. It's a huge market problem. I think the first point you mentioned is actually
more important, the stigma, meme coins, NFTs, the TikTok, crypto influencers.
It's just become an industry that's associated with a lot of people who really good builders
don't want to associate with, unfortunately. And I think the way to measure that, and no one's done
this, I'd like to see it, is create the sanity profile on Hanger dating app.
And the same person in one, but just do AB testing. In one version, he's an AI founder.
In other words, he's a crypto founder. And then just see what the responses are.
I know that's kind of funny, but that drive is seen in behavior.
It speaks to the issue, yeah.
It speaks to the issue. And that's also reflecting how people say that they're
fintech founders, not crypto founders at weddings when they're meeting their
girlfriend's best friends or that stigma is real and people know it.
What I'd say is I'd like to say that people need to be more serious. So it goes away,
but that kind of happened. Permitialists, I think the industry is going to continue being
the way it is. And they'll always be the some cringe edge of it by nature for a while.
What I'd say to a founder is just think about opportunity to competition ratios.
It's my favorite argument. Yeah, I completely agree.
Crypto is one of the biggest opportunities, I think, in the world today. It's on par with AI
founders. Probably a lot of AI is going to open AI. I think that's a different topic,
but I think for founders on par with AI, for capital indicators, it's on par with
tech or more interesting as an opportunity size. But there's just not a lot of competition here.
So I think if you are a smart, hardworking, serious person, you can find your way in the
top SLD industry pretty fast if you come into crypto. And the stigma issue will be gone in
five, 10 years, and you'll be in a pretty good spot. So I think it's a great place for founders to
come. That being said, people obviously new founders don't fully agree with me because
there are not enough here. I agree. I think a lot of people, particularly younger people,
index towards what they think the largest opportunity is today. And there's not an
appreciation of, to your point, relative white space within a category, relative competition,
relative to the opportunity set. It's a very flawed way of thinking.
Yeah, you need to think about how many people are going to be competing with you. That's part
of why I left private equity. It was still a great opportunity, right? It's every private
company in the US. But the amount of competition was just vicious.
Yeah, I worked at a $10 million hedge fund. I thought it was a very hard job.
Everyone's trying to do what you're trying to do effectively. And in crypto, you have these
massive scale market inefficiency still, like the fact that some 80% of the money goes into
venture investing. And their private equity doesn't exist as an asset class. What kind of asset
class has that set up? Yeah. Do you know this Michael Mollison luck versus skill continuum
argument? Yeah. It's interesting. I would say for anyone listening, if nobody knows what they're
doing, it's all luck. Imagine you're playing Katon or poker. If no one knows what they're doing,
it's all luck. If a few people are doing, but most people don't know what they're doing,
all the money will go to the few people who know what they're doing. If you're playing Katon or
poker, any game in the world, and you know what you're doing and you're playing with your 10-year-old
cousin, you're going to win a disproportionate amount of time. But then once everybody knows
what they're doing, they know that the game theoretical optimal move at every step,
it becomes luck again. Because if you're playing with people who know how to do the
game perfectly, again, I don't know how public Katon is. I'd always think of that. If you're
playing with people who know how to play perfectly, it's your role. That's it. That's what determines
the outcome because it's being played at the most efficient level. And I think a lot of industries
are at that all luck because everybody is so good level right now. And I'd say, you know,
hedge fund, private equity are getting close to that. There's people who are better, but for the
most part, everybody knows how to build a model. Everybody knows how to run the channel checks
and use whatever data sort set is necessary. So you just don't have that ability to create
really large skill gaps with the rest of the market. And I think in crypto, you can still do
that if you come in at the stage market. Yeah, I love that framing. You don't want to be at that
table. That's achieved perfect efficiency. This is a nice segue because another topic I wanted
to get into with you guys is a literal processes and creating edge. And I mean, it can be said for
very efficient markets, I think probably even more effective in less efficient or less mature
markets. But how do you guys look at, in your context, creating edge and putting into place
processes, whether that's via LLMs, whether that's via other internal tools or processes
to give yourselves an advantage? Yeah, this has been my third topic over the summer. I think for
a while, we basically run fully on LLMs right now as a shop. I'd say we've done a really good
job of becoming an LLM first investment manager. And I think that's the beginning of a big trend
as well in itself. So basically, when we started, they actually before tech BT, believe it or not,
we decided to become a Python first modeling shop. That was what we called at the time.
We were like, okay, data streams here, you can just reuse code a lot. So let's spike the bullet.
Let's not use Excel and PowerPoint like we used to. Let's just build our all our models in Python.
And that was hard, but it was worthwhile because you could build a model for Ave one month. And
then instead of going through this process, we do with Excel, where you have to get new data,
put in the model, I'll stay up to 2 AM for four nights in a row, rehash the model, bring it back
to IC, and like have a discussion, you could have this much faster process where you just hit refresh
on your Python model. And then automatically, you have the new numbers going through your model
with a new price. And we've been doing this since we start. So basically, all of our underwrites,
we have a live model, you can hit refresh on it, and all new data will flow in. And we can have a
get on the IC discussions after noon and say, Hey, we haven't looked at this company in a while,
let's talk about it. And on the spot, we're having a discussion with the latest numbers,
updated models, that's already a big improvement over what happens in traditional shops like kind
of use Excel and PowerPoint. But then we got lucky, because the end of our second year,
tech to PT came out. And all of a sudden, being Python first really started to make a big difference.
Because we could just build a lot more financial models in much less time, because obviously,
LLMs can write a lot of code for you. So when you ask what does it mean to be an LLM shop,
I think first it means that LLMs are writing your models, we say, Hey, build me a model for this
company. This is how I think about it here, the four or five me drivers, I want five cases here,
the five cases, that's an LLM building that for us, we're talking to the LLM as if it was a
sugar analyst, and give me a comment. When it comes to building analyses, bar charts, line charts,
historical data, data packed work, we'll say, Hey, I want to see these 10 numbers,
you're automatically in the position, even though no one I are both analysts, we're doing the
analysis ourselves, we're in the position of a senior partner, but probably for him with 10
analysts working for him, because we can just spend all day asking for analysis, and getting them
back immediately. And that's a big, big change. If you think about the economics of an investment
manager, there used to be these really nice economies of scale, where if you were a billionaire
fund, you can afford 10 analysts, you could just do a lot more analysis than the three person shop
like they are. And that's no longer true. You can have 10 analysts, they can't do that much more
analysis than the two of us can do anymore, because the LLMs are just so good at getting it done.
I'd say right now, in an individual day is doing, I used to work at a shop of 10 people doing analysis,
or probably doing in a day, what that shop would do in two weeks, and working people when they were
10, just because of how efficient LLMs are for financial analysis, especially when you add in
streaming data. I think it also just changes not only the economics that comes to scale for firms,
but it also changes the way you think about doing analysis in the first place. Because before the
world was analysis constrained, you were doing a deal, it took you four weeks to build out a really
big model with PoweredDeck and the data pack. You couldn't do text that might work. It took a
month to do that. So you were going to do the same kind of high ROI analysis for every deal.
You're going to do your LBL model, you're going to do your three year revenue model, whatever.
Now, you can really have five instances of cursor running five analysis at the same time.
So you can start to throw in more and interesting models. And that's going to be, I think, a hard
transition for one that we're trying to really get ahead of. You can build a traditional TAM model,
you can do S-curve penetration, you can do an SIR model, which actually is a model where you have
recovery where people leave the product. You can run, it's a lot, but you can run multiple different
lenses and start to get into the idea of stacking these models together and averaging them out with
certain requirements to get better answers for your predictions. There's a lot to dissect there,
but we've gone from a world that's analysis constrained to one that is not analysis constrained
if you start LLM first and use those build models. And I think we're really just trying to
lean into that. A couple questions and follow up. The first one is, how many financial firms
do you think are operating this way? And I'll mention a second to just so you can address both.
But the second is, do you feel like it's equally enhanced your capabilities on the qualitative
research side, whether that's following the social presence of a company or assessing
individuals online presence? It's certainly enhanced our capabilities on the qualitative side.
The other side of modeling is every question is just deep research,
chat to PT, or just conversations with chat to PT. This is a lot faster too. It used to be that you
had to go find an expert in the industry, ask them questions, set up a call, ask them questions. So
on Monday, you want to research the industry. And by Friday, you have your first cut after
three or four extra calls, you spend a lot of money doing that. Now you just get on with
text to PT and you say like, Hey, explain the home equity investment market to me,
walking through growth over the last five years, what are the regulatory issues?
And you can get two hours of doing that or three hours of doing that is a lot of work.
There's a lot of knowledge. And I used to have to be for everything, for everything qualitative,
either deep research or not, we use it a lot on the qualitative side. I'd say
on the qualitative side, the big constraint for people is just the amount of hours they
dedicate to deep work a day. And that's an interesting question that we're wrestling with.
Most investment firms are set up around this meeting type day, where you show up, you have a
firm white meeting, you meet with some porcos, you meet with some founders, you meet your friends
who are also analysts, you do your model at some point during that day. But the reality is that
that schedule was like an evolutionary offspring of a different time before LLMs, where that was
the highest ROI would spend your day. But now I think the highest ROI day needs to include
four or five hours completely alone with an LLM, just asking questions. It's hard to carve that
out. So we've been trying to force ourselves to carve those four or five hours a day out,
you just spend with LLMs asking questions, because by far the most signal and knowledge
transmission per minute, it's hard to do that. Think about getting four or five hours out of your
day to spend with an LLM and doing high effort research. And then your first question was,
how many firms are doing this? I think for small firms, we'll see a lot of firms doing it, like
us. I think for big firms with hierarchies, it's really hard because the senior team is used to
getting a certain type of output. If you give them Python, they'll be, I don't know what this is,
don't give me this. Just build the Excel model. We've been doing it this way for 20 years or 30
years or whatever. So I think that big firms are going to be really actually hard causing the cross
because the senior team will just not want to go out of the way to learn a new modeling technique
where a new way of working, where they could make a big mistake in the meantime,
if they miss an assumption because they're just kind of not used to the way that the
code looks on the page. Most of these people are pretty comfortable. They have a lot of money,
they've been doing it for a while, they have a way of doing things. My guess is small firms,
you'll see a lot of them doing it. Big firms will take a lot longer than people expect right now.
Yeah, I think you make important points. One on the path dependence. This was actually a point
of the same podcast you mentioned from Invest Like the Best with Neil Mehta, but he made an
important point where he said, a quality of the best founders he's seen is their ability
to block out everything that's not the one or two most important things at the moment.
And to your earlier point, I think the difficult part of taking the time to set up Python workflows
to take five to six hours a day in deep research is not actually doing it, which I think people
might think. So it's saying no to everything else, which could be your alternative marginal
opportunity cost of time. Yeah, I think that's right. I want to touch on a few points as we
start to wrap up here. What do you guys think of the regulatory environment and how has that
impacted your job? How do you look at it on a go forward basis?
It's definitely been a large tailwind for our industry. I think that we've started to spend a
lot of our time looking at traditional financial markets and understanding where the inefficiencies
are and which ones will be first to tokenized assets or tokenized funds, whatever it may be,
to blend that into how we see the growth of the companies that we're investing in today.
Just because I think that the proliferation of crypto-native assets making their way into
DeFi is continuing to play out is probably somewhere in the middle of the process. A large
percentage of the native assets are on these various DeFi applications. So at this point,
I think the marginal growth has to come from exogenous assets that are currently on blockchains.
So now that regulatory barriers are starting to be reduced and there's more experimentation
by traditional firms, it's definitely an area that we're trying to get ahead of.
Additionally, around that vein, I think speaking to early movers that are traditional financial
firms coming into the space and looking to get involved, so whether that's Janice Henderson
that's working with Centrifuge or Apollo that's tokenizing Acred, I think understanding how they
see the space and where their interest lies is also important. So I would say it's really just
understanding what the major drivers are going to be for the companies we're looking at as a by
product of the regulatory direction moving in a way that we see as being favorable. Outside of that,
it's keeping track of where the regulatory direction is moving. And so we have these bills
that are constantly moving through Senate. So reading through them, understanding the implications
for current market dynamics in case that these things are disruptive. So the stablecoin side
Circle and Tether are the two major players. Circle historically has had a pretty big regulatory
moat. Depending on how the genius act played out and other stablecoin bills played out,
it had pretty large impacts as to whether Circle would continue to have regulatory moat or whether
that regulatory moat would be declining. So you naturally need to get ahead of how those policies
may play out as well. So speaking to regulators, I think has pretty high ROI as well.
Yeah, it'll make sense. It's going to be an exciting, I would say 24 months. And I think we're only
seeing the tippy iceberg on the stablecoin and related front. I want to leave off by tossing
you guys one more point here and an opportunity to share some of your experience and beliefs.
But I want to know what's one investment thesis or idea that historically you feel like you've
gotten right? One that you held that didn't or hasn't panned out and then one that you feel
most strongly about looking down the line and feel free to tackle those in whatever order.
Makes sense. I can start with one that we have strong conviction in going forward.
That's one of the more exciting ones I've linked. Some good podcast topic.
MetaDow is the future key platform on Solana. We've publicly made two large OTC investments
into MetaDow. I think it is one of those really big ideas in HITJO.
Can you speak to what that means? It basically, future key is a governance system where you have
a decision. So let's say the decision is, should Apple bring back Steve Jobs as CEO?
And then instead of having him vote, you separate out two markets. One where you trade Apple stock
in a situation where Steve Jobs does come back as CEO. And one where you trade Apple stock
in a situation where he is not the Pepsi CEO remains in place. And just trust me for now
that the markets work. They're true markets based on that condition. And then you look
at the two markets and see where Apple stock trades higher. And that determines the outcome
of the decision. So if in this case, presumably the market where Steve Jobs comes back will trade at a
40%, let's just say premium to the other market, and the market has spoken on what is the better
decision for the stock price, and that ends up feeding into the actual decision. Just one really
quick example, say Uniswap wants to turn on their fee switch, or better yet, say Uniswap wants to
send revenue to Uniswap Labs. Instead of having that be a decision made by the team or by a
governance vote, you just put up the unit token and see whether it trades higher in a case where
revenue is sent to Uniswap Labs or higher in a case where that motion fails. And it's not sent
back to Uniswap Labs. Again, two examples. But basically, the reason we think Futurkey is
there's two views on Futurkey. One is strong Futurkey, which is like the market will make
a better decision on everything. Just always defer what you have for lunch or how you design a
product, or if whether you hire or fire this VP to the market, we don't believe in kind of strong
Futurkey. What we believe in is Futurkey as a board of directors. So when it comes time to changing
CEO, making an acquisition, selling the company, releasing a second token, restructuring the
token, we think that Futurkey markets should decide in that case. And the reason we think it's so
important is because the market essentially acts as the replacement as an enforcer of token holder
rights. So this goes back to something that we talked about all the time, which is the token
holder problem. Right now, token holders don't have regulatory protection, so they get fleeced
all the time. Cash flows are sent to the equity entity instead of the token. Teams launch a second
token where they have more an outside share just to kind of make a profit. Teams pay themselves
way, way way way too much as a way to just withdraw funds from the treasury. All these problems are
really, really serious problems in token markets. We think they're existential. I think we've talked
about the ad nauseam in the past. They make it very unattractive for capital flowing to token
markets. And a Futurkey kind of board of directors system solves all those problems. Because all
of a sudden it's like, oh, should we launch a second token where the CEO has 50% of supply,
market automatically will vote no on that. Because the main token will trade lower,
indicates where that happens. Or should we do M&A with some centralized exchange,
where they pay out the team, they pay the team a huge big bonus, but the token gets nothing.
Token would obviously vote that down. It becomes kind of trivial to vote down
attacks against token holders through this mechanism. So we see it as an enshrining of the
token as the objective function for a token business, which is very important. That happened
in US capital markets when in a court case called Doge versus Ford, where Henry Ford tried to
donate a lot of profits to charities of his choice. And the Doge brothers who were investors in
Ford sued him and said, your job is to maximize shareholder value. In the Supreme Court of the
US, I agree with him. That's where the fiduciary duty, the maximize shareholder value comes from.
And it's worked great in US capital markets over the past 200 years. We think that Futurkey is
that moment, is the Doge versus Ford moment in internet capital markets. And without it, I think
you live in this mean coin trader land where nobody wants to buy and hold because they're just
not protected. And with it, I think you have a better mechanism than you have in US capital markets
for protecting shareholders. That's why it's important. Now, why is it going to take off?
Just frankly, like if you raise money on Futurkey markets, investors are more willing to give you
the money because they know they're protected. We had an experiment called Mountain Capital,
I don't know if you followed that at all, where this team raised a few million dollars to invest in
Solana accelerated projects. And they were able to raise through metadata and it went quite well.
And then there was some strategy drift along the way where the team was not going to be as
involved as some investors like us that they would be, maybe the deals would be different than
they initially could pose with Solana accelerated projects. And that's the type of thing that could
lead to a big fight in regular internet capital markets, unprotected, or could lead to very unhappy
investors. But in this case, there was just a vote to return capital. And every single person who
held kept their money kept 100% principal. So that shows you what the protection means. And
then as an investor looking at an experiment, I'm way more willing to invest in it. If I know
that my downside is I can pull back funds. If the team, if it's not what I thought it was,
then if the way that we've really normally worked is if you invest in an experiment in
internet capital markets, invest in a token, and it doesn't work out well, you're getting a zero.
So the math and that is just a huge difference. But anyway, that's our go forward idea.
Know anything else on past or present? Yeah, just on past ideas that I think we've gotten right.
I think that we noticed that lending and credit was a more attractive market
post election compared to volume based businesses on chain. I think there's a few things. There's
the regulatory change and what that means for both sets of KPIs. So when you look at volume based
businesses, meme coins and other on chain assets that have price discovery that are on chain,
a very high turnover relative to their market cap and are generally somewhat ephemerally priced.
So they make for relatively low quality assets, but very high volume based assets, whereas the
marginal assets that occur or that exists publicly outside of crypto tend to have much
lower volatility. While you might see a very large amount of assets come on chain and dollar
value, it won't necessarily amount to a significant amount of trading activity just because they're
going to be lower turnover. We see the marginal assets coming on chain as being much better
collateral assets than the assets that exist on chain today, but don't necessarily see it leading
to a substantial spike in volumes just given that the kernel amount of volumes that occur on
trading trillions of dollars a year is quite large relative to the aggregate amount of volumes that
are going through traditional financial markets, whereas the total amount of assets that sit on
chain is a fraction of 1% of the total financial assets that exist broadly. And I think that's
generally starting to play out in markets and that volume based businesses, even with a lot of
activity that's occurred this year, have not gone much past their all-time highs in Q4 2024,
whereas TVL and Barrow Outstanding has gone to new all-time highs for many of the primary
lending businesses in the space. Yeah, I think it's a great insight. And for what it's worth,
I still love lending as a category on a go forward basis with this in mind and the number of assets
that'll come on chain that to me are conducive to flowing through those sorts of businesses.
This has been incredible. I want to thank you guys for coming on again and I hope to chat with you
again soon. Thanks for having us on. Thank you for having us. Thanks for listening to another
episode of On the Brink with Castle Island. To find out more about Castle Island, visit castleisland.vc.
To listen to all of our podcast episodes, please go to onthebrink-podcast.com
or just click on the tab in our website. Thanks for listening.